rodemic.com 2016-11-19

# RØDE Microphones - Privacy Policy

At RØDE we take your privacy very seriously. RØDE’s commitment to our web users' privacy and the full disclosure of our information gathering, dissemination and storage practices is evidence of that commitment. The data we collect is not sold, traded or made accessible in any way to any other company.

This policy, together with our  Terms of Use  sets out the basis on which any personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. 

**1\. Information we may collect from you**

1.1 We may collect and process the following information about you:  
(a) Information that you provide by filling in registration forms on the RØDE website www.rode.com (our “Site”). This may include personal details like Name, Address, Gender, Age, Employment, Telephone number, Email Address, and other relevant user information required and thereafter provided at the time of registering to use our Site, posting material or requesting further services; Information that you provide when you enter a competition or promotion, respond to an offer and when you report a problem with our Site;  
(b) Information that you provide when you choose opt-in services;  
(c) If you contact RØDE, we may keep a record of that correspondence;  
(d) Information provided by you in surveys requested by RØDE for research purposes, whether or not you respond fully to them; and/or  
(e) Details of your visits to our Site [including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise] and the resources that you access. 

**2\. IP addresses and cookies**

2.1 Our Site and its sub domains may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify you or any individual.  
2.2 Our Site and its sub domains may obtain information about your general internet usage and movement through the Site by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our Site, to personalise delivery of content, to facilitate quick logins, to speed up searches, to estimate our audience size and usage pattern, and to better understand how visitors negotiate our Site structure and its content.  
2.3 You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting in your browser preferences which allows you to refuse cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Site, you may need to re-enter your details each time you visit our Site and may limit the automatic delivery of content. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our Site. 

**3\. Where we store your personal information**

3.1 The data that we collect from you will be stored at a secure destination at RØDE’s discretion, and will be maintained and processed solely by RØDE. RØDE employs systems to ensure the security and integrity of all user information in our custody, and RØDE will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  
3.2 Where RØDE has given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.  
3.3 Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although RØDE will do its best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site, and any transmission is at your own risk. Once RØDE has received your information, RØDE will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

**4\. Uses made of the information**

4.1 The RØDE Microphones web site collects user information. The user information that RØDE collects is not sold, traded or made accessible in any way to any other company or organisation. By providing this information, users automatically consent to the use of the information by RØDE in the following ways:  
(a) To present RØDE products and to provide information about RØDE, its products and its services;  
(b) To issue RØDE mailings and newsletters;  
(c) To provide access to the benefits of RØDE offers and promotions;   
(d) To ensure that content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;  
(e) To allow you to participate in the interactive features of our Site, when you choose to do so; and  
(f) To notify you about changes to our Site.

**5\. Disclosure of your information**

5.1 We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries.   
5.2 We may disclose your personal information to an affiliated authorised distributors, retailers and/or service agents for the purposes of fulfilling RØDE’s warranty obligations.  
5.3 We may disclose your personal information to independent third parties only in the following circumstances:  
(a) In the event that RØDE sells or buys any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets, subject to strict confidential disclosure provisions;  
(b) If RØDE or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets;  
(c) If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our  Terms of Use  , or to protect the rights, property, or safety of RØDE, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction; and/or  
(d) If the user has opted–in for the provision of all or part of that user’s personal information to be provided to a third party for the purposes of marketing and promotional purposes. 

**6\. Your rights**

6.1 If you do not want RØDE to use your personal information as set out in herein, please tick the relevant boxes situated on the user registration form on which RØDE collects your information at the time of submission. This will allow you to opt-out of all or part of the uses of your personal information set out herein.   
6.2 If you have provided information to RØDE and thereafter you wish to opt-out of all or part of the information set out herein, or to remove your details from the RØDE database, please email your request to [privacy@rode.com](mailto:privacy@rode.com). RØDE will do everything it can to adhere to your request. 

**7\. Links**

7.1 Our Site and its sub-domains may, from time to time, contain links to and from external websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. The privacy practices of these organisations are outside the control of RØDE. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that RØDE does not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check their policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**8\. Access/Changes to information**

8.1 You have the right to access information held about you. Any access request may be subject to a fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. You also have the right to request the modification or updating of your information if at any time your circumstances change.   
8.2 Please email any such requests to [privacy@rode.com](mailto:privacy@rode.com) and RØDE will do everything it can to adhere to your request. 

**9\. Testimonials**

9.1 RØDE may at times receive information or stories from users about our products and their application with the intention of posting them on the RØDE website. Users are advised that the information they are submitting becomes public information and RØDE reserves the right to edit the information as required.  
9.2 The copyright of any words and/or images submitted by a user in this regard will remain the property of the user, subject to a general, irrevocable, worldwide licence granted by the user to RØDE to use the words and/or images for the purposes of testimonials on our Site and in other material in RØDE’s sole discretion. 

**10\. Liability**

10.1 RØDE shall not be liable for any of the following in respect of personal information held by RØDE: loss of personal information; corruption of data files regarding the information; inadvertent release of personal information; personal information illegally obtained by computer hacking; and/or personal information obtained by any third party beyond the control of RØDE. 

**11\. Changes to our Privacy Policy**

11.1 RØDE reserves the right to change all or part of this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes RØDE may make to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

**12\. Jurisdiction and Applicable Law**

12.1 The Australian courts will have non-exclusive jurisdiction over any claim arising from any aspect of this Privacy Policy. 

**13\. Contact**

13.1 Any questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy, the practices of the RØDE website, or your dealings with the RØDE website should be addressed to:

**The Webmaster**  
RØDE Microphones  
107 Carnarvon Street  
SILVERWATER NSW 2128  
AUSTRALIA
